<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>express on Werick Codes</title>
    <link>/tags/express/</link>
    <description>Recent content in express on Werick Codes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 1960-2095, Erick Wachira; all rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/express/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Add Api Rate Limits to Your Express Api</title>
      <link>/blog/how-to-add-api-rate-limits-to-your-express-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/how-to-add-api-rate-limits-to-your-express-api/</guid>
      <description>I had an idea of building a public API, sort of similar to the Marvel API, where you get to fetch all Marvel characters.
When I was brainstorming on how I would build the API, I thought about three key things: * It should be public and everyone should access (take note) * An admin account to allow me to update the API&amp;rsquo;s content.
The problem with making it public as it would be quite risky especially when someone runs a bot that results in DDoS attack happens and well the API will be free and I will be paying for the server costs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create a Node App Within a Docker Container With Mongo</title>
      <link>/blog/how-to-create-a-node-app-within-a-docker-container-with-mongo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/how-to-create-a-node-app-within-a-docker-container-with-mongo/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This is the second part of the series for Docker meets NodeJS where we are going to introduce a database service, MongoDB, which we will connect to it with our Node app through a network.
 Note: Since we are introducing a new database service, by doing so this also makes our Node app also a service
Note: Ensure you go through the first part of this series since it contains a huge part of how we created our Node app within a Docker container.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>